Tirivashe Shamhu

+263776202079 | shaymusts@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/tirivashe | github.com/Tirivashe

Summary

Software developer experienced in web, mobile, and full stack development. I enjoy learning and researching over newer and/or better technologies and languages, and have an ability to solve problems, team play, embrace mentorship and collaborate effectively to advance the development and completion of projects efficiently. I am also willing to relocate, if required.

Experience

React Frontend Developer

 $January\ 2022-Present$

Gaborone, Botswana

Letshego Holdings Limited

- Meeting with the development team to discuss user interface ideas and applications.
- Reviewing application requirements and interface designs.
- Identifying and analyzing over 100 web-based user interactions, resulting in 20% increase in website engagement.
- Developing responsive web application using React, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, and associated JavaScript frameworks, for desktop, tablet, and mobile platforms, achieving site traffic increase by 30% over 6+ months.
- Work with UX/UI Designers, architects, and other developers to implement full stack web and mobile solutions.
- Developing and implementing front-end architecture to support user interface concepts, which resulted in improved website performance by 20% and reduced page load time by 35%.
- Translating designs and wireframes into high quality code. Translated over 100 designs and wireframes into high quality code, resulting in a 25% increase in website functionality
- Documenting application changes and developing updates
- Work as part of an Agile Scrum team that successfully completed an average of 4 sprints within a 3-month timeframe, delivering all project deliverables on time and within budget

Software Development Engineer

June. 2019 – June 2021

Nashville, TN, USA

Intrinsic Value LLC

- Developed a web application's UI/UX and backend for an access control and domestic alert system using React JS, Node, JavaScript, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS S3 and Express.js.
- Full stack development and maintenance of the complementary mobile application using React Native
- Extensive and robust research and applying technical knowledge for the website's functionality and implementation of features necessary to the final product. Achieving this saw an increase in investors' interest, resources towards the product and higher demand for the product.
- Utilized JavaScript frameworks for front-end such as React, Node and third-party modules for form validation, geolocation, push notifications, Google Maps API, user login and other interactive features.

EDUCATION

Lipscomb University

Nashville, TN, USA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Aug. 2015 - May 2019

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Go, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML/CSS, Solidity, Kotlin

Frameworks: React, Node.js, Next,js, Node, GraphQL, Mantine UI, Tailwind, Material-UI, Nest.js, Jetpack Compose,

Hardhat, Ethers.js, Dagger-Hilt, Room, Retrofit, Coil

Developer Tools: Git, Github, Github Actions, Docker, Jira, Azure DevOps, VS Code

Concepts: Object-oriented programming, Data structures, Algorithms